alphamom.com 2008-06-12

# Alpha Mom™ - Baby, Pregnancy, Toddler, Motherhood, Baby Names, and Baby Product Reviews

ALPHAMOM.COM™ PRIVACY POLICY

Thank you for visiting the Alpha Mom™ website (the “Website”), located at www.alphamom.com. The Website is an Internet property of Alpha Mom™ TV, Inc. (the “Company,” “we” or “us”). We have created this privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) in order to disclose our information gathering and dissemination practices. We understand the importance that Internet users place on privacy and have designed the Website with this in mind. Alpha Mom™ is fully committed to one hundred percent (100%) permission-based marketing. You agree to this Privacy Policy, in its entirety, when you: (1) access or use the Website and/or Services; (2) agree to receive e-mail from us by indicating consent on the Website or via any other means; (3) provide any Personal Information (as that term is defined hereinbelow); and/or (4) participate in any sweepstakes or promotions that may be available at the Website.

This Privacy Policy will address the following:

1\. What information the Website gathers/tracks about you.  
2\. What the Website does with the information it gathers/tracks.  
3\. With whom the Website shares the information it gathers/tracks.  
4\. The Website’s opt-out policy.  
5\. The Website’s policy on deactivating your name from our database.

**Information Collected**

The Website enables users to view and/or submit consumer product ratings; view and comment on any Website columns; view editorial reviews of products; view, add names and/or submit ratings to the Baby Name Database; view information and/or videos on topics that may be of interest to users; enter any sweepstakes that may be available at the Website; and other information and/or services that may be available at the Website (collectively, the “Services”).

**Online Registration with Alpha Mom™**  
We provide an online registration form to process your request to enter any sweepstakes or promotions that may be available at the Website. Understand that the information that you submit is voluntary, but required if you wish to enter any sweepstakes or promotions that may be available at the Website. Upon registration, users may be required to provide personal information on the registration form that may include, but not be limited to, all or some of the following (collectively, “Personal Information”): 

1) Name;   
2) Postal address;  
3) Telephone number;   
4) Date of birth;   
5) Email address;   
6) Gender;  
7) Number and age(s) of children;  
8) How often you visit the Website; and   
9) How you heard about the Alpha Mom™ promotion; and  
10) How much time you spend on AlphaMom.com each week.

**Online Registration with Ning.com**  
The Alpha Mom™ Product Ratings System and the Alpha Mom™ Baby Name Database are powered by Ning.com. In order to access the Alpha Mom™ Product Ratings System and/or Baby Name Ratings System, users who do not already have a Ning ID and password will be required to register with Ning.com. Upon registration, users may be required to select a Ning ID and password for login purposes, and to provide a valid email address. Information provided to Ning.com in connection with registration for the Alpha Mom™ Product Ratings and/or Baby Name Ratings Systems will be jointly owned by Ning and Alpha Mom™. Alpha Mom™ does not endorse, nor is Alpha Mom™ responsible for, the privacy practices of Ning. For information regarding Ning’s privacy practices and terms of service, please visit the Ning.com homepage, located at www.ning.com.

Alpha Mom™ will not sell, lease or rent your personal information. Alpha Mom™ reserves the right to transfer and/or sell aggregate or group data about Alpha Mom™ users for lawful purposes. Aggregate or group data is data that describes the demographics, usage or other characteristics of Alpha Mom™ users as a group without disclosing personally identifiable information. By submitting your Personal Information to, and/or using, the Website, you agree to allow Alpha Mom™ to transfer and/or sell such aggregate data to third-parties and/or affiliates. Users that register for our services and/or any sweepstakes or promotions that may be available at the Website may receive e-mail messages confirming their registration with Alpha Mom™, as well as promotional marketing of commercial products and services.

**Online Registration with Movable Type**  
The Alpha Mom™ column comment system is powered by Movable Type, owner of the registration system “TypeKey”. In order to submit a comment to any column(s) that may be available at the Website, you may be asked to submit your full name and email address or you may register via TypeKey, if you do not already have a TypeKey display name and password. As a part of your registration via TypeKey you may be asked to provide your full name and email address and to select a display name and password. Your display name and password will be used for TypeKey login purposes in the event that you wish to post additional comments on columns in the future. Information provided to Movable Type in connection with registration for the Alpha Mom™ column comment system will be jointly owned by Movable Type and Alpha Mom™. Alpha Mom™ does not endorse, nor is Alpha Mom™ responsible for, the privacy practices of Movable Type. For information regarding Movable Type’s privacy practices and terms of service, please visit the Movable Type/TypeKey homepage, located at www.typekey.com.

**Website Tracking Software**  
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer the Website. Your IP address is used to gather broad and specific demographic information, as well as for validation purposes. Web servers, or those of third party vendors, utilize certain tracking software to capture your domain name address (the address of your Internet service provider) for purposes of tracking Website statistics. Note that we only collect information about you when you voluntarily provide information through registration. The capture of your domain name is a common practice among Websites for measuring the number of hits, pages visited and length of your session. We use this information to measure the effectiveness of the Website offering in order to serve you better.

**Cookies**  
We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password so that you do not have to re-enter it each time that you visit the Website (if you choose), and for other purposes. For more information on cookies, including how to disable them, please visit www.cookiecentral.com.

**Sharing of Information**  
We use the Personal Information that you supply to personalize your experience with the Website, process your registration for the services and for verification purposes. The Personal Information that you submit to Alpha Mom™ remains your property, but by submitting that Personal Information to Alpha Mom™ you grant Alpha Mom™ the right, subject to applicable state and federal law, to use that Personal Information for marketing purposes. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, we reserve the right to share/distribute any and all Personal Information with/to third-party agents and independent contractors that help us provide Alpha Mom™ services including, but not limited to, suppression, validation and e-mail marketing purposes. You agree that we may contact you at any time with updates and/or any other information that we may deem appropriate for you to receive in connection with your continued use of the Website.

Alpha Mom™ will not rent, sell or lease your personally identifiable information to any third party for marketing purposes. Non-personally identifiable information, such as demographic information, may be shared with advertisers on an aggregate basis. We also use contact information from your Personal Information to send you information about Alpha Mom™ and to keep you informed of our other products and services that may be of interest to you. Your contact information is also used to reach you, when necessary, regarding issues concerning your use of the Website and the Services. If you wish to stop receiving future communications from us, please see the Opt-Out/Unsubscribe section below. 

By submitting your e-mail address at the Website, entering any sweepstakes and/or promotions that may be available at the Website and/or registering for the Services, you agree to receive e-mail marketing from Alpha Mom™. In addition, you agree that such act constitutes a purchase, an inquiry and/or an application for purposes of the Amended Telemarketing Sales Rule, 16 CFR §310 et seq. (the “ATSR”). With respect to the ATSR, and notwithstanding that your telephone number may be listed on the Federal Trade Commission’s Do-Not-Call List, Alpha Mom™ retains the right to contact you via telemarketing in accordance with the terms of the ATSR. 

Alpha Mom™ reserves the right to release current or past user information and Personal Information: (A) in the event that we believe that the Website and/or Services is/are being or has/have been used in violation of the Website Terms and Conditions or to commit unlawful acts; (B) if the information is subpoenaed; or (C) if Alpha Mom™ is sold or acquired. Moreover, you hereby consent to disclosure of any record or communication to any third-party when Alpha Mom™, in its sole discretion, determines the disclosure to be appropriate including, without limitation, sharing your e-mail address with other third-parties for suppression purposes in compliance with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003, as amended from time to time.

**Other Websites**  
The Website may contain links to other third-party owned and/or operated websites including, but not limited to, Ning.com. Alpha Mom™ is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. In some cases, you may be able to make a purchase through one of their third-party websites. In these instances, you may be required to provide certain information, such as a credit card number, to register or complete a transaction at such website. These third-party websites have separate privacy and data collection practices and Alpha Mom™ has no responsibility or liability relating to them.

**Security**  
All collected information is stored in a technically and physically secure environment. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Personal Information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make reasonable efforts to ensure its security on our systems. Access to this information is strictly limited, and not accessible to the public. All of our users' information is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example customer service representative) are granted access to Personal Information. Our employees are dedicated to ensuring the security and privacy of all Alpha Mom™ user information. Employees not adhering to our firm policies are subject to disciplinary action. In compliance with applicable federal and state laws, we shall notify you and any applicable regulatory agencies in the event that we learn of an information security breach with respect to your Personal Information. You will be notified via e-mail in the event of such a breach. Please be advised that notice may be delayed in order to address the needs of law enforcement, determine the scope of network damage, and to engage in remedial measures. 

**Minors**  
Visitors under eighteen (18) years of age are not permitted to use and/or submit their Personal Information at the Website. Alpha Mom™ does not knowingly solicit or collect information from visitors under eighteen (18) years of age. Alpha Mom™ encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate and monitor the interactive activities of their children.

**Opt-Out/Unsubscribe**  
To stop receiving future communications from Alpha Mom™, please [Click Here](http://www.alphamom.com/optout_page/). To opt-out of having your information shared with third-parties, please [Click Here](http://www.alphamom.com/optout_third_parties/). Alpha Mom™ uses Personal Information to provide promotional offers by e-mail to individuals. Alpha Mom™ may maintain separate e-mail lists for different purposes. If e-mail recipients wish to end their e-mail subscription from a particular list, they need to follow the instructions at the end of each e-mail message to unsubscribe from the particular list. To unsubscribe from all Alpha Mom™ e-mail lists, please [Click Here](http://www.alphamom.com/optout_page/). 

**Changes in Privacy Policy**  
Alpha Mom™ reserves the right to change or update this Privacy Policy at any time by posting a notice at the Website explaining that we are changing our Privacy Policy. The user's continued use of the Website, Services and/or continued receipt of Alpha Mom™ e-mails constitutes an affirmative acknowledgment and acceptance by the user of the modified Privacy Policy. 

**Contacting the Site**  
Our “Contact” page contains information that allows you to contact us directly with any questions or comments that you may have. We listen to or read, as applicable, every message sent to us and endeavor to reply promptly to each one. This information is used to respond directly to your questions or comments. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the practices of Alpha Mom™, please feel free to contact us at (212) 752-7349 or at [contact@alphamom.com](mailto:contact@alphamom.com).

EFFECTIVE DATE: MAY 14, 2007
